Herbert Holder

Software Developer

- (469) 490-2334
- Herbrholder@gmail.com
- in linkedin.com/in/herbertrholder
- GitHub/HerbertHolder
- Portfolio

A passionate results oriented Software Engineer and US Marine Veteran with experience specializing in designing custom software solutions and driving new feature development. A proven track record of colaborating, excellent leadership and communication with teams throughout the application development cycle. Adept at defining user requirements and driving scalability for customers. Proven knowledge in debugging, troubleshooting and improving time and space complexity. Knowledgeable in data structures and algorithms.

Technical Skills

HTML, CSS,SASS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, Linux, NPM, C++,Java SE, J2EE, Java EE (Servlets, JSP), Spring, Thymeleaf, MySQL,

Object-Oriented Programming,
Test-Driven Development, Version
Control with Git, Paired
Programming, MVC, Relational
Databases, Hibernate, Maven

Exposure to: Unit testing / Unit test, AWS, JPA, JUnit, Scrum Methodology, Agile development, Restful web services, Rest API, Project Management Skills, CI/CD, Javascript Frameworks (React), Sprint Planning

Soft Skills

Mentoring, CSS,SASS, Bootstrap, Leadership, Reliability, Ability to Adapt, Communication Skills, Problem Solving Skills, Collaborate

Development Projects

Algorithm Analysis:

https://replit.com/@HerbertRHolder/SortingProject20#main.cpp

This is a program that uses most of the known computer science algorithms and puts them against each other to measure how fast/efficient each algorithm becomes given a specified circumstance. This circumstace is the percentage of randomness vs ordered items in an array. Depending on specific input, each algorithm's time complexity could slightly differ, some negligible and others drastically.

Algorithms used: Merge Sort, Insertion Sort , Selection Sort , Heap Sort, and Quick Sort.

Movie Project: https://swann-holder-zhang.github.io/Movies-project/

This application displays movies to the user. This application allows the user to create, read, update, and delete movies from a JSON server. This application uses an object-oriented database and implements CRUD operations.

Environment: HTML, CSS/SASS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, JSON Server

Aviato: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IIYdMmmSo2g

An agile, ecommerce full-stack project designed to provide users with a seamless flight booking and purchasing experience. Aviato users can easily search, select, and purchase flights. The application integrates with flight APIs and data sources to ensure comprehensive coverage and accuracy of flight schedule information. Aviato also features a user-friendly interface that enables users to view and manage their current bookings. They can check flight numbers, departure and arrival times, and booking status. Additionally, the project includes secure storage and protection of user data and payment information to comply with relevant data protection regulations.

Environment: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, MySQL, Java, and Spring Boot.

Education

Codeup

Certification of Completion March 2023

A fully-immersive, project-based, and intensive 20-week Full-Stack Java Career Accelerator that provides students with 670 hours of expert instruction in software development

Linkedin Certification

Relational Databases
Certification of Completion
Sept 2022 - Oct 2022
Identifying relations. Defining a
database that is flexible in terms
of the questions a user can ask.
Recall the characteristics of a
Lookup Table.Recognize
situations in which
denormalization would be
beneficial.

Understand the types of relationships modeled by junction tables.

Defining referential integrity.

Borough of Manhattan Community College

New York, NY Computer Science

Pace University

New York, NY Computer Science

Military Experience

U.S. Marine Corps | Camp Pendleton South, California Supply Administration Logistician | 09/2013 - 09/2017

- Analyzed and coordinated the ongoing logistical functions of a firm or organization. Responsible for the entire life cycle of a product, including acquisition, distribution, internal allocation, delivery, and final disposal of resources.
- Maintained and developed positive business relationships with customer
- Developed an understanding of the customer's needs to take action ensuring that such needs are met.
- Review logistics performance with customers against targets, benchmarks, and service agreements.
- Accomplished the technical duties in retail and wholesale accounting, multimedia data entry, and generating routine reports.
- Maintained custody records of digital and physical copies of over 10 million dollars in receipt documentation every fiscal year for 2 years resulting in 98% retrieval rate.
- In charge of ordering large bulk of gears from various vendors.
 Shippings part over sea and where needed
- Very seldom use FedEx, DHL, and UPS for small part
- Utilized Microsoft Excel and data entry software applications (Oracle) to keep track of government property and ordered items using (\$2 million worth) government funding.

Professional Experience

C3 Engineering Services - Irving, Texas

IT Technician and Logistics Specialist | Jun 2021 - Oct 2022

- Planning, directing, and organizing the shipment and delivery of goods and services. Worked with long supply chains across multiple regions and time zones. Bringing the correct parts together in the correct quantity at the correct time.
- Managed the distribution of finished products to the final user
- IT technician Help desk engineer utilizing "Datto Autotask" and "N-Able RMM" to remote in on workstations and manage SLA tickets.
- Tracked and recorded inventory, monitoring delivery schedules and scheduling deliveries and pickups.
- Integrate computer components utilizing Motherboard Architectures to build an efficient workstation.
- Planned, directed, and organized the shipment and delivery of goods and services utilizing Vendor/shipment tracking services such as Service Bench and GSFS.
- Successfully met SLA targets via a ticketing deadline system

Jets Services | Bronx, NY

Customer Service Representative | Mar 2019 - Jan 2020

- Conversed with others to convey information effectively.
- Actively looked for ways to improve customer sentiment.
- Developed constructive and cooperative working relationships with team members.
- Discussed goods or services information with our patrons.